And the mother cried,
"Is this myself I see,
reflected in your eyes?"
And the daughter said,
"Is it me I see,
mirrored in yours?"
Helena.
Come back.
She's going to make you do twice
as many chores when you get back.
I don't mind the trade.
Maybe if we're gone long enough,
she'll forget she's mad.
Okay.
We'll walk slow, Little Shadow.
It was here.
Running or walking?
The strides are wider
than before.
And deeper on the outsides.
It was running.
Why?
Because it was scared
of something.
Scared of what?
Us.
If you were afraid,
running for your life,
where would you go?
Where no one could see me.
It's time you finished the hunt.
What if I miss?
Then we go hungry tonight.
I didn't make a sound.
So, what do you think happened?
It smelled me.
You won't need the fire.
Helena,
come get what you earned today.
She's always mad at me.
Oh, your mother
can't see happiness like we do.
Okay.
I'm fine.
It's getting late.
Helena, no more.
Where's the rest of it?
It's free now.
It chewed its own leg off?
Sacrificed what it had to,
to survive.
When can I keep mine
in the house like you do?
When you're as good a hunter
as I am.
Which will be never.
What do the marks say?
They say,
"When you're running
from an angry moose,
beware of low branches."
I heard it crying.
She's starving.
Well, we have some
scraps inside. We could maybe..
What happens
when those are gone?
There's nothing more pure
than the instinct to survive.
The wolf holds no pity.
Just the desire
to live another day.
What would you do to the wolf,
if you were starving?
You're its prey.
We all are.
But what about the baby?
Will suffer and die alone.
Now, do what I say, Helena.
- But if..
- Helena, move.
You must always
protect your family.
Nah.
This is one of my alone trips.
- But I can help.
- No, come on. You know the rules.
- I'll bring you back a surprise.
- What kind of surprise?
Kind of surprise you're gonna
have to wait to find out what it is.
Now, get on back there.
I'll be home soon.
Sorry to come ridin' in on you.
Is your mom or dad around?
Hey.
Hope I'm not trespassing
or anything.
Didn't know
anybody lived way out here.
Been out for hours,
and I got all spun around. I..
I can't find my way back
to the trail.
No signal out here anywhere.
Look, if you could just
point me toward..
Help!
Please. Before he gets back.
What?
What are we doing?
What are.. What are you doing?
Get on,
Helena. Whoa. Hang on.
- He'll be back soon.
- Who?
- Please, we have to go. Now!
- I..
- I don't wanna go!
- I can't just take you.
I'm not even sure where we are.
That's why I'm..
No!
Mother! Mother, stop!
Mother! Mother, stop! Stop!
- Helena!
- No!
Father!
Helena?
- Father!
- Helena?
No!
Stop! Stop!
Somebody!
Look who's awake.
It's okay, Helena.
Your mother's
just in the next room.
Where's my father?
He's not here. You're safe now.
There's nothing
to be afraid of anymore.
Don't worry about that.
Helena.
We shouldn't be here.
I want to go home.
- That wasn't our home.
- What did you do?
What did you do?
- I want Father.
- He can't be near us.
Ever again.
He took me, Helena.
Jacob...
kidnapped me
and took me to the woods.
You're lying.
You're a liar.
You have always been a liar.
Father told me.
Stop crying!
You're not allowed to do that.
We need to let your mother rest.
Just for a few minutes.
We'll be okay. Helena?
Father?
- Who's out?
- Yeah.
Okay, we have to go. Come on.
You did good. Come on.
Okay, let's go this way.
- There he is!
- Police! Don't move!
Are we gonna go home?
One day we will.
Hey! Don't move!
Back away from the girl.
No!
On your stomach!
Now!
He didn't do anything wrong.
Let me see your hands.
I'll come find you,
Little Shadow.
He's running! I got him!
- Hands behind your back!
- Daddy!
Shoot.
No running, Marigold.
Hi, sweetie.
Mrs. Haver said she has a life of
her own, and if you're gonna be late,
she's gonna
start charging you rent for me.
She did,
huh? What does that mean?
It means you are so valuable,
she thinks I should pay for you.
Whatcha got here?
- My science project.
- It's a habitat. Uh-huh.
Habitat? Who's the habitat for?
A baby deer.
It sleeps over here, beside the rocks,
to keep it safe from hunters.
Smart deer.
Mommy!
What kind of leaf is this?
A walnut.
- From which tree?
- You tell me.
There.
Mm-hmm.
And what's that tree?
A red oak.
It doesn't look red to me.
It will be in the fall.
Do you see the bird?
A wood thrush.
How do you know all the names?
I can teach you if you want.
I can see a bunny rabbit.
Where?
You have to kind of
tilt your head. See the ears?
Oh, yeah. I see it.
With the tail down this way?
Yeah.
It means that we're one.
Family.
Mom?
When can I have one of these?
Not until you're 82 years old.
That's the rule, remember?
That's not fair.
You got them
when you were young.
I was much older than you,
and I wish I hadn't.
I like them.
I like you.
Daddy's home!
Put your stuff inside, sweetie.
We're going to the campus
for Daddy's work picnic.
- Picnic?
- Sorry we're late.
I forgot about
your thing tonight.
That's all right. Let's just go.
I have to change. Why don't you go
on over with her, and I'll come later.
Well, we've tried that.
You never show.
I'm just not good.
- At those things. - Neither am I.
Which is why you're coming with.
Plus, you're my beautiful wife,
and I want to show you off.
You know, it's funny.
Thank you.
- Hey, you good?
- Yeah.
Is Marigold having fun?
I don't know.
The crazy thing is,
my students don't even try
to hide it anymore.
Phones are going off
my entire lecture.
Well, in their defense,
I have heard some of your lectures.
I love that. It's unusual.
- Oh, thanks.
- Did you get it around here?
Uh, in San Francisco,
when I was a teenager.
You have a bunch of them.
Too many.
I didn't know
you're from San Francisco.
Other places too. - We moved around a lot.
- What'd your parents do?
My father worked in insurance,
my mom sometimes did telemarketing.
Doesn't get much more boring
than that.
"Then she took 20
mattresses and laid them on the pea."
On this, the princess
had to lie all night.
In the morning
she was asked how she had slept.
And the princess said...
"'‘Oh, very badly.'"
What's going on?
Where's my daughter?
Helena Erikkson?
Where's Marigold?
She's not here.
This isn't about her.
I'm Special Agent Illing.
What are you doing in my house?
- Ms. Erikkson.
- My name is Pelletier.
Before that,
it was Jones, correct?
Then Mitchell,
after you changed it from Bekkum.
But you were born to Jacob
Holbrook and Beth Erikkson.
What do you want?
Your father, Jacob Holbrook.
He and another prisoner
escaped last night
while being transported across
the state line to Alger Penitentiary.
When's the last time
you spoke to him?
When I was ten years old.
- Has he tried to contact you recently?
- No.
Are you sure? Not even once?
You could've called me.
You didn't need to come here.
What's going on?
You okay?
Do you know where your father
might be going?
Y-Your father?
You can't just
come into my house.
Our warrant allows us to
check for any possible communication
to or from your father.
Why do you keep saying that?
Helena's father..
He doesn't know where I live,
doesn't know my last name,
doesn't know anything about me.
And that's same for your
family and friends? Have any of your..
I've never told anyone
Jacob Holbrook is my father.
So, 20 years.
No letter,
birthday card, anything?
No.
I'm confused.
I thought your parents died
in a car accident.
That's what I told you.
And Holbrook, that's the Marsh
King guy. The one that just escaped.
I heard it on the radio.
That's right.
Is there any risk
of him coming here?
That's what we're trying
to find out.
He doesn't know where I live.
Oh,
you can't be too sure of that.
Christ, Helena.
How could you not have told me?
I told you to stay in the car, sweetie.
- Who are these people?
- Police. They're just..
I'm gonna take her.
I'll call you later.
We're gonna need to see
your phone and any computers you use.
With any luck,
your father will be found soon.
You don't know my father.
If he makes it to the wild,
you'll never see him again.
In a case that received
nationwide notoriety,
Jacob Holbrook, the so-called
"Marsh King," abducted Beth Erikkson
and held her for 12 years
in the wilderness
of Michigan's Upper Peninsula,
until she eventually escaped
with the daughter she gave
birth to while in captivity.
After the trial, Erikkson had
difficulty adapting to normal life
and was rarely seen in public.
Tragically, she died four years
ago in an apparent suicide.
Yeah?
You guys coming home?
I grabbed a hotel room
for the night. Mari's in the pool.
I could bring her over
some school clothes, if you want.
I'm keeping her out tomorrow,
just in case.
I didn't think
this would happen.
That I'd find out?
No. I mean, I wish I..
Mari's yelling for me.
I gotta go.
Little Shadow.
Time to check our snares.
And a real hunter...
needs a real knife.
This is yours now.
Let's see how you do with it.
Hi.
I called earlier,
but you didn't answer.
I'm not great with phones.
That's an understatement.
I saw the news.
Thought I'd shoot down
and say hello.
Hello, Clark.
Maybe grab a glass of water
before I head back.
I know you
don't want me dropping in,
but I figured
everything's changed a bit now.
Cat's outta the bag.
How's your husband taking it?
Not well.
He'll come around.
Just a matter of time.
The little one's
not so little anymore.
Your mother
would've loved to have met her.
I thought you might bring
Marigold up home a while back,
at least for the funeral.
She wouldn't have
met her then either.
That's true enough.
Then, I guess I meant
I wish you woulda come sooner.
She would've liked that.
He still has that job
at the college?
You still doing..Nothing's changed.
Okay.
This is not how I saw this
playing out.
I'm sorry,
I just can't do this right now.
Well,
at least it's not in the press.
No one's putting you with him.
Just wanted to make sure you
weren't worried about things.
I'm not.
You know, there was a space
when you were about 13 or so.
I thought we had a shot at bein'
a nice little family, the three of us.
It was never the three of us, Clark.
She didn't want me around.
When she looked at me,
she saw my father.
So did you.
No.
You're forgetting
some good days.
She loved you.
I still love you.
I miss you.
But sure, maybe sometimes
we saw a little Jacob in you.
Or maybe you never saw
enough of him in me.
You here to relieve this
fella? No, I'm supposed to..
Mrs. Pelletier, the FBI would
like you to come down to the office.
Did something come up?
Way above my pay grade.
You want me to come with you?
We found your father's body.
Just inside the state line.
We assume they were heading
for a crossing to Canada.
Guard rail, 60 feet up on the
embankment was splintered.
Driver either lost control
or fell asleep.
The car hit a tree
and caught fire.
Both men were burned
beyond recognition.
We think they had an accomplice.
We're looking for him now.
How can you be sure
it's Holbrook?
He has three gold teeth with
carvings matching your father.
You all right?
My father died 20 years ago.
Mmm.
I'm sorry about your daddy.
We saw it on TV.
Thank you, sweetie,
but he wasn't my daddy for a long time.
We brought you some food
in case you didn't wanna cook.
Let me guess, extra pepperoni?
- I'm definitely in the mood for pizza.
- Yes!
How you doing?
I'm fine.
I wish you would've told me
the truth.
What's the worst
that could've happened?
- We wouldn't have Mari.
- You don't know that.
Yes, I do.
Who in their right mind would
get involved with the daughter...
If you knew my name was Holbrook,
you'd never have gone on a date with me.
You would've run the other way.
- You will now.
- Hold on.
Let's pretend that I'm a better
person than you think I am, all right?
What's the best thing
that could've happened?
You might've found
somebody to trust.
Someone to help you through
all the shitty days.
Somebody to explain
all your weird tattoos to.
The best never happens, Stephen.
No matter how badly we want it.
- Marigold okay?
- Yeah.
She's asleep.
Do you really believe that?
What you said before about...
the best never happening.
Because if you do,
what's that mean for us?
Look I.. I don't wanna
make this any worse for you.
But you gotta let me in, Helena.
Okay, look. I'm gonna go
do some work at the office.
Probably sleep over there.
My name is Helena Holbrook.
Remember the guy
who kidnapped that woman?
The one everybody called
The Marsh King?
I'm his daughter.
Sometimes I sneak off alone
at night because I feel trapped.
Like I can't figure out
which world I really belong in.
I have trouble trusting
people because...
everyone tells me the
person I believed in the most
was really a monster.
He gave me this
after my first kill.
And this one when I missed.
This is the place
he taught me to swim.
The name he gave me.
This to remind me never to wait
to do my chores.
These were the only tears
my father ever wanted to see.
Would you like to go out
on a date with me?
Come on. I
know. I can do it.
I have been looking forward
to this day.
Thought it was time to
introduce you to a couple people.
Look, Daddy,
they have horses.
This is Clark. He's gonna try his
best to get you to call him Grandpa.
Make him earn it.
That doesn't scare me a bit.
I've got no one else
to spend it on.
It is very nice to meet you, Marigold.
You too, Clark.
I'm gonna like this one.
Would you like
to see the horses?
Who's getting hungry?
Two hours after I took that,
I started getting calls
that some hoodlum
was setting off fireworks
in people's yards.
She tore that dress to shreds,
running from one of my deputies.
You can stop now.
Oh, hell, we haven't even got
to your difficult stage yet.
Who's that?
That's your grandmother.
You definitely take after her.
I don't remember that picture.
It looks like us.
You know, I wouldn't complain
if this became a habit.
Thank you, Clark.
Anytime.
Hey.
You know,
Jacob took a lot of my people's beliefs,
twisted 'em
to fit what suited him.
Means "owned" in Ojibwa.
Not "family."
Don't confuse the two.
Sh..
Little Shadow.
What's wrong?
I'm just getting some water.
Hey, make sure you wipe
your feet when you come in the house.
I did.
I'll drop her on the way.
See you after.
- We'll go swimming or something.
- Don't forget my goggles.
I got that conference
in Detroit this afternoon.
Might be home late.
- You gonna be okay?
- Mmm.
Thank you.
Helena?
How you doing?
Good. Fine.
Are you guys
around this weekend?
I was thinking Jess and Marigold
could have a playdate.
Oh, yeah. I think we're free,
just...
Sorry. Yeah, she'd love that.
How's Saturday? Would she
like to come over to our place?
Of course. She has swim
until 10:00 but after that...
Can you hold on a second? Sorry.
You're not helping.
I'm not supposed to help.
This is your homework, not mine.
But you always help.
Well, you can figure this out.
Why are you in a bad mood again?
I'm not.
I don't mean to be.
Let's go read. We'll get Daddy
to help us finish in the morning.
- Okay?
- Okay.
"Water lilies spread
over the surface of the pool"
like a carpet patterned
with flowers.
And on this carpet,
lay a young and beautiful woman.
The mother cried, '‘Is this myself
I see, reflected in your eyes?'
"And the daughter said..."
Hey, daughter?
You missed your entrance.
Helena.
- What is it?
- It's a doll.
You.. You play with it.
Like a friend.
She has hair like me.
A tiny Helena.
Oh, God.
Marigold!
Helena!
Hey, it's me.
It's me.
Jesus. What are you...
Uh... I..Whose blood is that?
No one's. A rabbit.
I heard somebody outside.
Maybe try calling the police
instead of running around
in the dark with a knife.
- I have to check on Marigold.
- Marigold's fine. She's asleep.
I just left her room.
Did you see anyone out there?
Hey.
We're gonna keep the doors locked,
all right?
Get a few cop cars on patrol.
It's gonna be okay.
It was bleeding
from the head.
Like someone killed it first,
then put it in the snare.
Or maybe it got injured
some other way.
What's got you spooked? Why do
you think there's something more?
I feel like he's here.
The night you found us,
when we came out of the woods,
I was so afraid
because he wasn't there with me.
But then he came.
Don't get lost in this, Helena.
Now he's come back again.
I have to tell him
to leave us alone.
You have got to try to get him
out of your head.
For good.
I'm not sure
I can do that.
How could he be alive?
I don't know.
There's nothing purer
than the instinct to survive.
Mommy!
Marigold?
I couldn't find my backpack.
Oh, no, no, no. That stays here.
I wanna show people.
Let's wait a while on that, okay?
Okay.
Where did you get those?
I thought you made them.
I like them.
Looks like you and me.
Has the habitat been in
your room the whole time?
Mm-hmm.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Stay inside
after school unless Daddy
or I are here, okay? Don't go with
anyone else, no matter what they say.
What's this about?
Just felt like it.
Can you pick Marigold up
after school?
Of course.
Why?
I have to do something.
I can't tell you what it is.
What's going on, Helena?
I know I haven't
given you any reason to...
please trust me.
I'll call you when I get back.
Back from where?
Last secret, Stephen.
Promise.
You and Mari rescued me.
I can call it anything I want?
It's yours.
I gave it to you.
I name it
Helena Falls.
Hello, Little Shadow.
Let's go for a walk.
How did you find me?
I never lost you, Little Shadow.
I miss that smell.
And the taste.
Gimme that.
My favorite knife.
We used to come camping up here,
you remember?
We'd lay out here
all summer long.
Look up at the sky,
see who could count
the most shooting stars.
I used to cheat
and count airplanes.
You knew I was alive the whole time,
didn't you?
I didn't know
how it was possible.
Not until I saw
a three-legged coyote.
Sacrificed its own leg
for freedom.
Like you sacrificed your teeth.
Ah.
Probably won't pass
a medical exam,
but it bought you
the time you needed.
You did some digging.
Well done.
You didn't tell anyone else
your theory?
Did you?
Wish you'd brought Marigold.
Tell me about my granddaughter.
I don't think so. You know
enough about her already.
Well, I had to take a peek.
You never brought her
to visit me.
You didn't visit me at all.
Come on, Little Shadow.
I want to show you something.
You know,
Marigold looks like her.
Your mother.
I bet she loves the water
as much as we do.
That's to take us
across the border.
The three of us.
To Canada,
we can be a family again.
I have a family.
You have a daughter.
And a husband.
We've built a life together.
Are you happy with that life?
Not always.
Do you ever think
back to what it was like
when we lived here?
- I do.
- We can have it all again.
I remember
when you were four years old,
you could shut your eyes
and you knew where you were
from the sound of the water,
from the smell of the trees,
and the feel of the ground
beneath your feet.
It was like magic.
This is where we belong.
It's our home.
Our life here
was perfect.
No!
Don't you ever run away
from me again!
Okay? You hear me?
I wasn't..
Perfect?
Not for my mother.
Well, it could've been.
How?
- You kidnapped her.
- No. We ran away together.
That's just something she said
when she decided to leave.
- You shot that man.
- I was trying to hit the engine.
You never would have missed.
I missed.
You've been told a
bunch of stories about me.
They're not true. I never was the
Marsh King, until they said I was.
I know this, we were happy.
You were happy.
All I'm saying, bring Marigold,
let her see for herself.
I can't do that.
I won't.
I'm sorry.
This is where it ends.
I shouldn't have come here.
I'm glad I did.
Now I have to go home
to my family.
Please don't come
near them again.
- It doesn't need to be like this.
- It does.
Okay.
I understand.
You'll always be
my Little Shadow.
I have to go.
Clark?
- What are you doing here?
- Could ask you the same thing.
Stephen called me.
He was worried.
And I just had a hunch
after what you said.
- Is he here?
- Let's go back. I'll tell you on the way.
Helena, was he here?
But he's gone.
Clark. Clark.
Clark. Oh, God. Oh, God.
Clark, look at me, okay?
Clark. Clark, stay with me.
You told him. - You were coming here?
- No, I didn't say anything.
Please, look at me.
Clark, I'm right here.
Clark, hold on.
Please, Clark, hold on.
You must've said something.
Make your stepfather curious.
Enough to wander out here
all this way by himself.
Just get away from us.
What have you done?
Please, Clark. Please. Come on.
Come on. Please.
Well, there's nothing you can do
to help him now.
No!
You'd rather the wolf lived
than us?
You want it to feed you
to its pup?
Now I have to get Marigold
on my own.
No! Don't you touch her!
We can still all be a family.
It's all I want.
I'll be back with Marigold soon.
No! No, no.
No!
Helena.
Wrap the rope around you.
Did he say I could come up?
I don't care,
I'm getting you out of there.
I've got you, my Helena.
You're gonna be fine.
Because you're stronger than me.
Braver than me.
Please.
Clark.
I'm so sorry.
I'll come back for you.
All rivers bend, Helena.
Is the blood warm
or cold?
- Cold.
Then you must move faster.
Running or walking?
Running.
And if you were afraid,
running for your life,
where would you run?
To where no one could see me.
You know what you taught me.
You're fine,
it's just a flesh wound.
Now...
what good will it do Marigold
if her mother is lying rotting
in the bottom of the marsh?
She needs you.
Just think about
what's best for your daughter.
Okay?
No!
The boat you came in. Show me.
Go on.
I waited my whole life
to see you again.
I wasn't sure what I would feel
when I did.
- What do you feel, Little Shadow?
- Don't call me that.
Not anymore.
I used to think you said it
because I was always beside you.
Now I realize you just meant,
like any shadow, I wouldn't
exist if you weren't standing there.
Your mother did a job on you
after I was gone.
No, she didn't.
I barely spoke
to her my whole life.
I blamed her for everything too.
I never believed her.
You really think she cared about
you the way I care about you?
She wouldn't have a gun on me.
She could have run.
Gotten away.
She stayed to protect me.
Now I know,
she was the strong one.
She was weak.
No.
A man who drags a woman
into the wilderness is weak.
Careful, Little Shadow.
You forget all the things
that I did for you.
The years I spent in a cage
'cause I came back for you.
What would you do for Marigold?
I'd die for her.
Daddy!
Come on. Come on.
"Water lilies spread
over the surface of the pool
like a carpet patterned
with flowers.
And on this carpet lay
a strong and beautiful woman.
The mother cried, '‘Is this myself
I see, reflected in your eyes?'
"And the daughter said..."
"Is it me I see,
mirrored in yours?"
"Then the child rose
in the shape of a mighty swan
and spread her powerful wings."
I don't hate you.
I don't pity you.
I just remember your lesson.
Always protect my family.